A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller papers FA002
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Financial Materials, F; 400 linear feet
  - Charities Index Cards, 1863-1903; V14; 9 boxes
    - University of Chicago - $82.58, 1901 (Box 8, Folder 1371)
      See also Chicago University and American Baptist Education Society-Chicago University.
    - University Settlement - $16,410.00, 1897-1899 (Box 8, Folder 1372)
      Miss Duncan Speyer, Joseph
    - Upshaw, William D. (for Monroe College) - $50.00, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 1373)
    - Urquhart, William - $25.00, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 1374)
    - Miss Valentine - $335.00, 1879-1896 (Box 8, Folder 1375)
      Davidson, C. A.
    - Van Duyne, Mrs. Augusta - $250.00, 1895-1901 (Box 8, Folder 1376)
    - Van Duyne, Mrs. Watson L. - $2,908.00, 1895-1902 (Box 8, Folder 1377)
    - Van Duyne, Watson L. - $150.00, 1895, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 1378)
    - Mrs. Van Duzer (Cleveland, Ohio) - $1,480.00, 1885-1903 (Box 8, Folder 1379)
    - Mrs. Van Horne - $50.00, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 1380)
    - Rev. Van Meter - $15.00, 1867-1869 (Box 8, Folder 1381)
    - Van Valkenberg, Miss A. - $25.00, 1888 (Box 8, Folder 1382)
    - Van Wert, Ohio Baptist Church - $100.00, 1886-1887 (Box 8, Folder 1383)
      Gardner, Rev. N. B. H. King, Rev. G. O.
    - Mrs. Vandergrift - $50.00, 1879 (Box 8, Folder 1384)
    - Vanderlip, Rev. George (for Rev. Dr. Williams) - $100.00, 1882 (Box 8, Folder 1385)
    - Vassar College - $460,907.59, 1880-1902 (Box 8, Folder 1386)
      Backus, T. J. Dean, W. L. Ellsworth, Ed. (treas.) Miss Ely Miss Hastings Miss Leach Taylor, Rev. J. M. Wood, Miss Frances A.
    - Vassar Southern Missionary - $10.00, 1867 (Box 8, Folder 1387)
    - Vaughn, George - $50.00, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 1388)
    - Vaughn, Mrs. Nettie - $75.00, 1890 (Box 8, Folder 1389)
    - Viaduct Celebration (Cleveland, Ohio) - $25.00, 1878 (Box 8, Folder 1390)
    - Virginia, Minnesota Lutheran Church - $300.00, 1895 (Box 8, Folder 1391)
      Krantz, Rev. J. A.
    - Virginia, Minnesota Methodist Church - $300.00, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 1392)
      Gary, Rev. O. J.
    - Virginia, Minnesota Presbyterian Church - $300.00, 1895 (Box 8, Folder 1393)
      Raymond, Rev. E. W.
    - Volunteers of America - $8,635.00, 1896-1902 (Box 8, Folder 1394)
      Booth, Ballington
    - Waddleton, Mrs. A. E. - $25.00, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 1395)
    - Wahpeton, Dakota Baptist Church (North Dakota) - $100.00, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 1396)
      Johnson, Mrs. Julia W.
    - Walcott, Gregory D. - $300.00, 1900 (Box 8, Folder 1397)
    - Waller, E. E. - $100.00, 1889-1891 (Box 8, Folder 1398)
    - Waller, Mrs. E. E. (Cleveland, Ohio) - $975.00, 1892-1902 (Box 8, Folder 1399)
    - Ward and Drummond - $6.45, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 1400)
    - Ward, Albert H. - $25.00, 1897 (Box 8, Folder 1401)
    - Waring Memorial Fund - $5,000.00, 1898 (Box 8, Folder 1402)
      Strong, W. L.
    - Waring, O. T. - $10.00, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 1403)
    - Warren, Rev. J. S. - $50.00, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 1404)
    - Washburn, Mrs. Miriam (Episcopal Church, Colorado) - $100.00, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 1405)
    - Washington & Lee University - $5,000.00, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 1406)
    - Washington Court House Baptist Church - $500.00, 1885 (Box 8, Folder 1407)
      Lloyd, Rev. E. W.
    - Washington Heights Baptist Church - $1,337.63, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 1408)
      Nelson, C. Alex.
    - Washington, Mrs. L. H. (daughter's tuition) - $1,400.00, 1885-1890 (Box 8, Folder 1409)
    - Waterbury, Mrs. M. A. - $670.00, 1887-1901 (Box 8, Folder 1410)
    - Waterbury, Mrs. M. W. - $900.00, 1898-1902 (Box 8, Folder 1411)
    - Waterbury, Mrs. S. A. - $100.00, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 1412)
    - Waterson, Mrs. M. G. - $25.00, 1895 (Box 8, Folder 1413)
    - Watkins Glen Baptist Church - $5.00, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 1414)
    - Watson, John (Titusville, Pennsylvania) - $100.00, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 1415)
      Hoag, E. C.
    - Watts, Margery - $50.00, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 1416)
    - Wausen Baptist Church - $10.00, 1868 (Box 8, Folder 1417)
    - Weatherby, Mary, 1900-1902 (Box 8, Folder 1418)
    - Webbers Falls, Indian Territory- $25.00, 1895 (Box 8, Folder 1419)
      Scales, Miss A. P.
    - Webster, Rev. S. B. - $1,575.00, 1878-1898 (Box 8, Folder 1420)
    - Weed, Thurlow (treas.) - $100.00, 1880 (Box 8, Folder 1421)
    - Weller, Mrs. R. J. - $324.87, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 1422)
    - Welles, Mary - $100.00, 1880 (Box 8, Folder 1423)
    - Wellesley College - $101,447.21, 1886-1900 (Box 8, Folder 1424)
      Hardy, A. H.
    - Welsh Baptist Church (New York) - $50.00, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 1425)
      Grier, Dr. W. F.
    - Welsh Church, Newburgh, Ohio - $155.00, 1869, 1886 (Box 8, Folder 1426)
      Hyde, G. A.
    - Wesleyan Church - $0.50, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 1427)
    - West High School - $200.00, 1895 (Box 8, Folder 1428)
      Starke, Helen L.
    - West Richfield Church - $100.00, 1887 (Box 8, Folder 1429)
      Fox, Rev. A. L.
    - West Side Baptist Church (Cleveland, Ohio) - $328.50, 1865-1889 (Box 8, Folder 1430)
      Rev. Thomas
    - West Superior Baptist Church - $200.00, 1891 (Box 8, Folder 1431)
    - Western Reserve College - $2,500.00, 1881 (Box 8, Folder 1432)
    - Western Reserve Historical Society (Cleveland, Ohio) - $10,400.00, 1892, 1899 (Box 8, Folder 1433)
      Cleveland, James D. Comer, Horace B.
    - Westfield, New Jersey Church - $20.00, 1897 (Box 8, Folder 1434)
      Miss Heller
    - Miss Westman - $100.00, 1901 (Box 8, Folder 1435)
      Schofield, Mrs. L. P.
    - Wetherby, Mary - $100.00, 1900, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 1436)
    - Wheeler, Laura - $6.00, 1892-1893 (Box 8, Folder 1437)
    - Wheeler, Mrs. Charles - $100.00, 1884 (Box 8, Folder 1438)
      Smith, Mrs. W. T.
    - Wheeler, Mrs. E. E. - $100.00, 1881, 1890 (Box 8, Folder 1439)
      Miss Ingersoll
    - Wheeling, West Virginia Baptist Church - $100.00, 1885 (Box 8, Folder 1440)
      Shott, G. M.
    - White, Mrs. J. P. - $3.00, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 1441)
    - Whiting (Mrs.) Fund - $250.00, 1886 (Box 8, Folder 1442)
      Teviso, Mrs. F. L.
    - Whiting, Indiana Baptist Church (gift was returned) - $500.00, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 1443)
      Hewitt, Rev. C. E.
    - Whiting, Mrs. Mary R. S. - $100.00, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 1444)
    - Whitney, Miss M. L. (for poor family) - $40.00, 1888-1889 (Box 8, Folder 1445)
    - Whittaker, C. (political purposes) - $250.00, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 1446)
    - Whittier Homestead - $100.00, 1898 (Box 8, Folder 1447)
      Frankel, Mrs. Annie W.
    - Willard, Frances E. - $100.00, 1884 (Box 8, Folder 1448)
    - Mrs. Willard - $65.00, 1866, 1884 (Box 8, Folder 1449)
      Carse, Lillie B.
    - Willard, Mrs. C. E. - $414.00, 1898-1902 (Box 8, Folder 1450)
    - Williams, Mrs. J. C. (education, oldest boy) - $1,010.81, 1889-1893 (Box 8, Folder 1451)
    - Willow Mission Chapel (Cleveland, Ohio) - $1,000.00, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 1452)
      Brotherton, Rev. H. Rockefeller, F.
    - Wilson Avenue Baptist Church (Cleveland, Ohio) - $8,025.00, 1878-1901 (Box 8, Folder 1453)
      Garber, R. A. (treas.) Goodwin, E. L. King, G. O.
    - Wilson Avenue Methodist Church (Cleveland, Ohio) - $100.00, 1884 (Box 8, Folder 1454)
      Irvine, Mrs. L. M.
    - Wilson Industrial School (New York) - $200.00, 1887-1902 (Box 8, Folder 1455)
      Huntington, Emily Stone, Mrs. A. B.
    - Wilson Street Hospital (Cleveland, Ohio) - $25.00, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 1456)
    - Wilson, George (Secretary of Chamber of Commerce) - $100.00, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 1457)
    - Wilson, Elizabeth - $40.00, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 1458)
      Mrs. Fletcher
    - Mrs. Wilson - $25.00, 1895 (Box 8, Folder 1459)
      McLean, Alex
    - Winans, Mrs. Emeline - $1,064.00, 1894-1903 (Box 8, Folder 1460)
    - Windermere Presbyterian Church (Cleveland, Ohio) - $100.00, 1897 (Box 8, Folder 1461)
      Wilson, Mrs. G. M.
    - Windom Fund - $1,000.00, 1891 (Box 8, Folder 1462)
      Knox, John Jay
    - Wisconsin Baptist State Convention - $4,000.00, 1897-1902 (Box 8, Folder 1463)
      Dinsmore, F. C. Hurlburt, D. W.
    - Wisher, Rev. D. W. - $350.00, 1884-1886 (Box 8, Folder 1464)
      Judson, B. F.
    - Miss Wolcott (Miss Hyland) - $25.00, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 1465)
    - Women's and Children's Dispensary (Cleveland, Ohio) - $5,799.98, 1882-1902 (Box 8, Folder 1466)
      Mrs. Dr. Jennings McDonald, Dr. Ella J. Merrick, Dr. E. J. Parsons, Dr. Kate S. Stine, Dr. M. M. Waterson, Helen F.
    - Women's Baptist Foreign Mission Society - Tremont Temple - $3,250.00, 1881-1902 (Box 8, Folder 1467)
      Clarke, Mary E. Burr, Mrs. Josephine Burr Hornby, Mrs. A. Paddock, Mrs. C. H. Steadman, Miss A. (treas.)
    - Women's Christian Association - $171.00, 1869-1893 (Box 8, Folder 1468)
      Chandler, Miss Frances
    - Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU) - New York - $50.00, 1884 (Box 8, Folder 1469)
      Alford, Mrs. C. C.
    - Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU) - State Work, Ohio - $4,641.83, 1889-1890 (Box 8, Folder 1470)
      Barnes, Mrs. W. J. Perkins, Sarah M. Phinney, Ellen J. Mrs. Prather Woodbridge, Mrs. Mary A.
    - Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU) - Venongo, Pennsylvania - $50.00, 1891 (Box 8, Folder 1471)
      Hulings, Mrs. M.
    - Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU) Nonpartisan (Cleveland, Ohio) - $26,865.00, 1884-1903 (Box 8, Folder 1472)
      Adams, Mrs. Edgar Mrs. Burrowes Mr. Cogswell Gribble, Hattie Ingersoll, M. E. Phinney, Mrs. E. J. Mrs. Prather Mrs. Zeman
    - Women's Exchange (Cleveland, Ohio) - $25.00, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 1473)
      Miss Chandler
    - Women's home (Cleveland, Ohio) - $5.00, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 1474)
    - Women's Hospital, New York (corner 4th Avenue and 49th Street) - $200.00, 1898 (Box 8, Folder 1475)
      Thompson, Mrs. F. T.
    - Women's Hotel Association - $200.00, 1898-1899 (Box 8, Folder 1476)
      Miss Bowly Kellogg, Charles D.
    - Women's Missinoary Union - $35.00, 1887 (Box 8, Folder 1477)
      Rudd, Mary E.
    - Women's National Indian Association - $1,100.00, 1893-1902 (Box 8, Folder 1478)
      Quinton, Mrs. A. S. Taggart, Mrs. P. S.
    - Women's National Sabbath Alliance - $25.00, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 1479)
      Van Nest, Mrs. F. R.
    - Women's Relief Fund (Cleveland, Ohio) - $50.00, 1898 (Box 8, Folder 1480)
      Painter, Mrs. K. V.
    - Women's Temperance Society (Chicago) - $200.00, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 1481)
      Donnelly, Mrs. R. R.
    - Women's Training School (Chicago, Illinois) - $150.00, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 1482)
      Littlefield, Mrs. L. A.
    - Wood, George M. (Tickets for concert) - $9.00, 1890 (Box 9, Folder 1483)
    - Woodland Avenue Presbyterian Church - $750.00, 1879, 1891 (Box 9, Folder 1484)
      Severance, L. H.
    - Woodland Hills Railroad - $108.00, 1876 (Box 9, Folder 1485)
    - Woods, Rev. H. C. - $200.00, 1897 (Box 9, Folder 1486)
    - Woodward, Mrs. Mary Avery - $450.00, 1899-1903 (Box 9, Folder 1487)
      Avery, Miss Rowena (for) Avery, Mrs. Allen H. (for)
    - Mrs. Woodworth - $50.00, 1888 (Box 9, Folder 1488)
      Covert, Jno. C.
    - Wooley, Jno. G. - $100.00, 1895 (Box 9, Folder 1489)
    - Working Girls Vacation Society - $730.00, 1901-1902 (Box 9, Folder 1490)
      Bryce, Edith Dodge, Grace H.
    - Working Women's Protective Union - $500.00, 1894-1903 (Box 9, Folder 1491)
      Wright, J. Howard
    - World's Fair Enterntainment (Committee through Chamber of Commerce) - $666.67, 1893 (Box 9, Folder 1492)
      Simmons, J. E.
    - Wuertz, Maggie - $284.00, 1887-1895 (Box 9, Folder 1493)
    - Yager, Miss T. M. - $25.00, 1887 (Box 9, Folder 1494)
    - Yarmouth, Maine Baptist Church - $250.00, 1893 (Box 9, Folder 1495)
      Houghton, Dr. H. C.
    - Yellow Fever Sufferers - $50.00, 1878 (Box 9, Folder 1496)
      Eells, D. P.
    - Young Ladies Temperance League - $445.00, 1879-1885 (Box 9, Folder 1497)
      Bartlett, Jennie Prather, Mrs. J. S.
    - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) - Cleveland, Ohio - $72,969.66, 1867-1897 (Box 9, Folder 1498)
      Cowles, J. G. W. Fenn, S. P. Goodman, F. S. Morse, O. C. Rudd, W. C. Stockley, G. W. Shurtleff, G. K.
    - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) - Cleveland, Ohio, Railroad Branches - $700.00, 1879-1899 (Box 9, Folder 1499)
      Brainard, H. C. Gunn, Dr. R. A. Lindsey, T. S.
    - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) - Duluth, Minnesota - $800.00, 1894-1900 (Box 9, Folder 1500)
      How, C. F. (treas.) Olcott, W. J. Stevens, George W.
    - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) - East Cleveland, Ohio - $20.00, 1882 (Box 9, Folder 1501)
    - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) - Greenpoint, New York - $100.00, 1886 (Box 9, Folder 1502)
      McGee, Joseph
    - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) - International Work - $288,390.00, 1884-1902 (Box 9, Folder 1503)
      Morse, Richard C. Mott, John R. Schenck, F. B. Wetmore, B. C.
    - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) - New York - $112,257.50, 1885-1902 (Box 9, Folder 1504)
      Brown, W. P. McBurney, R. R. Orne, Henry M. Pyne, M. Taylor Sloan, S. Jr. Williams, Leighton
    - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) - New York - Bowery - $1,000.00, 1884 (Box 9, Folder 1505)
      Pyne, Percy R.
    - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) - Oil City, Pennsylvania - $950.00, 1887-1900 (Box 9, Folder 1506)
      Berry, J. M. Flint, E. H. Hukill, George P. Ingraham, P. S. Mather, W. S. McKenzie, D. R.
    - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) - Richmond, Virginia (Colored) - $500.00, 1890 (Box 9, Folder 1507)
      Jones, J. E.
    - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) - Students Club - $2,270.00, 1899-1901 (Box 9, Folder 1508)
      Sinclair, Jno.
    - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) - Training School, Springfield, Massachusetts - $3,500.00, 1899-1902 (Box 9, Folder 1509)
      Bowman, H. S. Marsh, Charles Morse, Oliver C.
    - Young Men's Hebrew Association - $50.00, 1886 (Box 9, Folder 1510)
      Piexalta, Mrs. B. F.
    - Youngstown Baptist Church - $100.00, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 1511)
    - Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) International - $100.00, 1896 (Box 9, Folder 1512)
      Messar, Mrs. L. W.
    - Mrs. Zimmerman - $424.00, 1878-1902 (Box 9, Folder 1513)
- Miscellany, Z
  This series consists of a variety of printed matter including personal calling cards, holiday greeting cards, cards imprinted with inspirational words, and a card to acknowledge appeals to Mr. Rockefeller for charitable contributions. A bound version of the "Last Will and Testament of John D. Rockefeller" is also included in this series.
  The material in this series is not dated.
  - Birthday Acknowledgement (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Card with envelope. "Mr. Rockefeller deeply appreciates your kind remembrance of him on his birthday and sends you his cordial greetings and best wishes."
  - Calling Cards (Box 1, Folder 2)
    "Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Four West Fifty-fourth Street" Contained in 2 original stationery boxes, tied with white ribbon, interleaved with tissue paper; 1 box contains envelopes.
  - Checks (Box 1, Folder 3)
    The Fifth Avenue Bank, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. National City Bank of New York, John D. Rockefeller
  - Declination of Requests (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Funeral - Dr. Fosdick's Prayer at the Funeral Service of John Davison Rockefeller (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Pocantico Hills, New York, May 26, 1937
  - Funeral - A Resolution on the Death of John D. Rockefeller, Sr. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    City of East Cleveland, Ohio, May 24, 1937. Embossed with City of East Cleveland seal.
  - Holiday Greeting Cards - "In the Gardens at Kijkuit" (Box 1, Folder 7)
    "Bless you for your Holiday Greetings. May the New Year be a very happy one for you."
  - Holiday Greeting Cards - "Kijkuit" (Box 2, Folder 8)
    "With hearty Christmas Greetings and all good wishes for the New Year."
  - Holiday Greeting Cards (Box 2, Folder 9)
    "With kindest thoughts and best wishes for Christmas and the New Year" Plain-edged and gold-embossed.
  - Holiday Greeting Cards (Box 2, Folder 10)
    "Bless you for your Holiday Greeting. May the New Year be a very happy one for you."
  - Inspirational Cards (Box 2, Folder 11)
    "The Best Memory System" "But as we meet and touch each day..." "I Do It Unto Thee" "It was early taught to work as well as play..." "Somebody did a golden deed..."
  - Last Will and Testament of John D. Rockefeller, June 2, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    4 copies, paperback, stitched.
  - Stationery and Envelopes - Ormond Beach, Florida (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Letter-sized writing paper, printed "John D. Rockefeller, Ormond Beach, Florida" Envelopes with return address "Ormond Beach, Florida"